Fransisca Rivan

Curriculum Vitae



PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm not the most experienced employee, nor the smartest nor the best. I'm not gifted with brilliances. That's what makes me try harder than others, not giving up, and always giving my best shot. I'm willing to learn, for learning is a lifetime progress, because success is never final and failure is never fatal, we only lose when we quit.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name : Fransisca Rivan

Sex : Female

Birth Place : Medan, North Sumatera

Birth Date : 06th of May 1989

Marital Status : Single

Residential Address: Niaga Grisenda Blok GE No. 39 Jakarta Utara 14460

E-mail : fransisca.rivan@gmail.com

Phone Number : +62 21 55965501 Mobile Number : +62 818 06009771

Nationality : Indonesian

WORKING EXPERIENCE

2015 – present Account Executive

PT. Perdana IMMG Indonesia

International Media Marketing Group (IMMG) Indonesia functions as the media marketing arm of Parent Company

- ADK. ADK is the third largest full service advertising

agency in Japan.

Account Executive in IMMG Indonesia works as the daily

business wheel, who is responsible for:

- Manage the workflow of client's campaign

- Find and negotiate with new clients

- Manage good relationship with existing clients
- Research and develop new creative and effective marketing strategies
- Expand company's networking

2014 – 2015 Assistant Manager

KidzArt Indonesia, Jakarta – Indonesia As the sole person in charge for KidzArt Permata Hijau branch, involved in planning, organizing, managing, and marketing.

Job Description:

- Lead staff in every aspects to develop the growth of KidzArt Permata Hijau
- Assist in business growth activities
- Third party relationship
- Student relationship
- Studio management
- Art instructor

2012 – 2013 Freelance Illustrator and Graphic Design, Jakarta – Indonesia

- Bali Dental Clinic
 - As graphic designer, redesign the branding needs of clinic such as logo, brochure, marketing kit, etc.
- Define Beauty Clinic
 As creative consultant and graphic designer, discuss creative branding strategy with owner, execute creative ideas into graphic designs.
- Whale Studio
 As graphic designer, create the creative needs of clients from Whale Studio.
- PT Gramedia Media Pustaka
 As illustrator, brainstorm and execute creative ideas into novels cover.

2012 – 2012 Junior Graphic Designer Saatchi & Saatchi Advertising, Jakarta – Indonesia Job Description:

- Brainstorm and develop creative ideas
- Execute ideas into graphic design

2011 - 2012

- Internship Junior Art Director
 The Drawing Squad Advertising, Jakarta Indonesia
 Job Description:
- Assist Art Directors in creative progress
- Brainstorm, develop, and design creative ideas
- 2. Internship Account Executive Lowe Worldwide, Jakarta – Indonesia Job Description:
- Assist Senior Account Executives
- Manage creative workflow

2009 - 2010

Lecturer's Assistant of Art and Design Faculty Tarumanagara University, Jakarta – Indonesia Job Description:

- Assist the lecturer while teaching in class
- Help student in learning progress
- Manage class when lecturer is away

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

2007 - 2012

Tarumanagara University, Jakarta – Indonesia

Faculty: of Art and Design

Study Program: Visual Communication Design

Bachelor Degree

Achievements:

- Best Graduate from Visual Communication Design study program, GPA 3.65
- Best Final Artwork from Visual Communication Design study program
- Awarded with one academic year scholarship for Achievement Category
- All achievements accomplished while active in university's organization, from member to leader level

2004 – 2007 Tarsisius Vireta High School, Tangerang – Indonesia

Study Program: Social

Achievements:

- First rank in social classes for 2 years in row

Committee of school organization

2001 – 2004 Santa Maria 2 Junior High School, Tangerang – Indonesia

1995 – 2001 Santo Fransiscus Primary School, Tangerang – Indonesia

INTERESTS

LEADERSHIP I have been trusted with responsibility of leading people

both informal and formal, e.g. as editor in chief, team leader, school's student committee coordinator, volunteer's coordinator, facilitator at trainings, etc.

As Editor in Chief for ArtMAX Magazine volume 4, I made

major positive changes, such as clearing all the

organization's debt, leave a significant surplus at the end

of my period, success in marketing, distribution: the

magazine distributed inside and outside the university for

the first time in my hand, created the first launching, succeed in regeneration by "friends of ArtMAX" strategy

where we involved new students for as volunteers

LIVING LIFE Life is too short to not be happy every day, and too short

to complicate. Just do the best in daily basis, because the

easiest way to predict the future is to create it.

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

2014 Co-facilitator at Innovasia Training Center for PT

Energasindo Heksa Karya and Pakarti's team building

training

2014 Co-facilitator at Innovasia Training Center for PT Star

Energy's team building training

2012 – 2013 Co-founder of PAW Rescuer, a domestic animal rescue

organization and later as the leading rescuer

2012	Committee of "The Legend of Princess Ong Tien
	Operetta" for Butterfly Dream Dance Group, Jakarta –
	Indonesia
2011 – 2012	Activist in domestic animal rescue, coordinating with local
	animal's rescuer such as Shelter Pejaten, 911 for Dogs, etc
2011	Facilitator of "Training of Trainer" from Tarumanagara
	University
2011	Instructor of University "Student Management Skill
	Training" at Tarumanagara University
2011	Instructor of University "Student Softskill Training" at
	Tarumanagara University
2010 - 2011	Editor in Chief of ArtMAX Magazine, Tarumanagara
	University, volume 5
2009 – 2010	Reporter of ArtMAX Magazine, Tarumanagara University,
	volume 4
2009	Volunteer Coordinator of Indonesia Graphic Design
	Awards (IGDA)
2009 – 2010	Volunteer of FDGI (Forum Desain Grafis Indonesia)
2009 – 2011	Member of Art & Design Student Committee (Badan
	Eksekutif Mahasiswa)
2009 – 2011	Committee of "Basic Leadership Training" of Art & Design
	Faculty
2009 – 2010	Committee of faculty's "Design Gathering" event
2008 – 2010	Committee of faculty's "New Student Orientation"
2008	Committee of faculty's "Video Week Competition"
2008	Committee of faculty's "Pentas Seni : Duabelasan"
2007	Committee of faculty's "Pentas Seni : Tradesainal"